Help on function area in module plotly.express._chart_types:

area(data_frame=None, x=None, y=None, line_group=None, color=None, pattern_shape=None, symbol=None, hover_name=None, hover_data=None, custom_data=None, text=None, facet_row=None, facet_col=None, facet_col_wrap=0, facet_row_spacing=None, facet_col_spacing=None, animation_frame=None, animation_group=None, category_orders=None, labels=None, color_discrete_sequence=None, color_discrete_map=None, pattern_shape_sequence=None, pattern_shape_map=None, symbol_sequence=None, symbol_map=None, markers=False, orientation=None, groupnorm=None, log_x=False, log_y=False, range_x=None, range_y=None, line_shape=None, title=None, subtitle=None, template=None, width=None, height=None) -> plotly.graph_objs._figure.Figure
        In a stacked area plot, each row of `data_frame` is represented as
        a vertex of a polyline mark in 2D space. The area between
        successive polylines is filled.
        
    Parameters
    ----------
    data_frame: DataFrame or array-like or dict
        This argument needs to be passed for column names (and not keyword
        names) to be used. Array-like and dict are transformed internally to a
        pandas DataFrame. Optional: if missing, a DataFrame gets constructed
        under the hood using the other arguments.
    x: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        position marks along the x axis in cartesian coordinates. Either `x` or
        `y` can optionally be a list of column references or array_likes,  in
        which case the data will be treated as if it were 'wide' rather than
        'long'.
    y: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        position marks along the y axis in cartesian coordinates. Either `x` or
        `y` can optionally be a list of column references or array_likes,  in
        which case the data will be treated as if it were 'wide' rather than
        'long'.
    line_group: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        group rows of `data_frame` into lines.
    color: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign color to marks.
    pattern_shape: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign pattern shapes to marks.
    symbol: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign symbols to marks.
    hover_name: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like appear in bold
        in the hover tooltip.
    hover_data: str, or list of str or int, or Series or array-like, or dict
        Either a name or list of names of columns in `data_frame`, or pandas
        Series, or array_like objects or a dict with column names as keys, with
        values True (for default formatting) False (in order to remove this
        column from hover information), or a formatting string, for example
        ':.3f' or '|%a' or list-like data to appear in the hover tooltip or
        tuples with a bool or formatting string as first element, and list-like
        data to appear in hover as second element Values from these columns
        appear as extra data in the hover tooltip.
    custom_data: str, or list of str or int, or Series or array-like
        Either name or list of names of columns in `data_frame`, or pandas
        Series, or array_like objects Values from these columns are extra data,
        to be used in widgets or Dash callbacks for example. This data is not
        user-visible but is included in events emitted by the figure (lasso
        selection etc.)
    text: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like appear in the
        figure as text labels.
    facet_row: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign marks to facetted subplots in the vertical direction.
    facet_col: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign marks to facetted subplots in the horizontal direction.
    facet_col_wrap: int
        Maximum number of facet columns. Wraps the column variable at this
        width, so that the column facets span multiple rows. Ignored if 0, and
        forced to 0 if `facet_row` or a `marginal` is set.
    facet_row_spacing: float between 0 and 1
        Spacing between facet rows, in paper units. Default is 0.03 or 0.07
        when facet_col_wrap is used.
    facet_col_spacing: float between 0 and 1
        Spacing between facet columns, in paper units Default is 0.02.
    animation_frame: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        assign marks to animation frames.
    animation_group: str or int or Series or array-like
        Either a name of a column in `data_frame`, or a pandas Series or
        array_like object. Values from this column or array_like are used to
        provide object-constancy across animation frames: rows with matching
        `animation_group`s will be treated as if they describe the same object
        in each frame.
    category_orders: dict with str keys and list of str values (default `{}`)
        By default, in Python 3.6+, the order of categorical values in axes,
        legends and facets depends on the order in which these values are first
        encountered in `data_frame` (and no order is guaranteed by default in
        Python below 3.6). This parameter is used to force a specific ordering
        of values per column. The keys of this dict should correspond to column
        names, and the values should be lists of strings corresponding to the
        specific display order desired.
    labels: dict with str keys and str values (default `{}`)
        By default, column names are used in the figure for axis titles, legend
        entries and hovers. This parameter allows this to be overridden. The
        keys of this dict should correspond to column names, and the values
        should correspond to the desired label to be displayed.
    color_discrete_sequence: list of str
        Strings should define valid CSS-colors. When `color` is set and the
        values in the corresponding column are not numeric, values in that
        column are assigned colors by cycling through `color_discrete_sequence`
        in the order described in `category_orders`, unless the value of
        `color` is a key in `color_discrete_map`. Various useful color
        sequences are available in the `plotly.express.colors` submodules,
        specifically `plotly.express.colors.qualitative`.
    color_discrete_map: dict with str keys and str values (default `{}`)
        String values should define valid CSS-colors Used to override
        `color_discrete_sequence` to assign a specific colors to marks
        corresponding with specific values. Keys in `color_discrete_map` should
        be values in the column denoted by `color`. Alternatively, if the
        values of `color` are valid colors, the string `'identity'` may be
        passed to cause them to be used directly.
    pattern_shape_sequence: list of str
        Strings should define valid plotly.js patterns-shapes. When
        `pattern_shape` is set, values in that column are assigned
        patterns-shapes by cycling through `pattern_shape_sequence` in the
        order described in `category_orders`, unless the value of
        `pattern_shape` is a key in `pattern_shape_map`.
    pattern_shape_map: dict with str keys and str values (default `{}`)
        Strings values define plotly.js patterns-shapes. Used to override
        `pattern_shape_sequences` to assign a specific patterns-shapes to lines
        corresponding with specific values. Keys in `pattern_shape_map` should
        be values in the column denoted by `pattern_shape`. Alternatively, if
        the values of `pattern_shape` are valid patterns-shapes names, the
        string `'identity'` may be passed to cause them to be used directly.
    symbol_sequence: list of str
        Strings should define valid plotly.js symbols. When `symbol` is set,
        values in that column are assigned symbols by cycling through
        `symbol_sequence` in the order described in `category_orders`, unless
        the value of `symbol` is a key in `symbol_map`.
    symbol_map: dict with str keys and str values (default `{}`)
        String values should define plotly.js symbols Used to override
        `symbol_sequence` to assign a specific symbols to marks corresponding
        with specific values. Keys in `symbol_map` should be values in the
        column denoted by `symbol`. Alternatively, if the values of `symbol`
        are valid symbol names, the string `'identity'` may be passed to cause
        them to be used directly.
    markers: boolean (default `False`)
        If `True`, markers are shown on lines.
    orientation: str, one of `'h'` for horizontal or `'v'` for vertical. 
        (default `'v'` if `x` and `y` are provided and both continuous or both
        categorical,  otherwise `'v'`(`'h'`) if `x`(`y`) is categorical and
        `y`(`x`) is continuous,  otherwise `'v'`(`'h'`) if only `x`(`y`) is
        provided)
    groupnorm: str (default `None`)
        One of `'fraction'` or `'percent'`. If `'fraction'`, the value of each
        point is divided by the sum of all values at that location coordinate.
        `'percent'` is the same but multiplied by 100 to show percentages.
        `None` will stack up all values at each location coordinate.
    log_x: boolean (default `False`)
        If `True`, the x-axis is log-scaled in cartesian coordinates.
    log_y: boolean (default `False`)
        If `True`, the y-axis is log-scaled in cartesian coordinates.
    range_x: list of two numbers
        If provided, overrides auto-scaling on the x-axis in cartesian
        coordinates.
    range_y: list of two numbers
        If provided, overrides auto-scaling on the y-axis in cartesian
        coordinates.
    line_shape: str (default `'linear'`)
        One of `'linear'`, `'spline'`, `'hv'`, `'vh'`, `'hvh'`, or `'vhv'`
    title: str
        The figure title.
    subtitle: str
        The figure subtitle.
    template: str or dict or plotly.graph_objects.layout.Template instance
        The figure template name (must be a key in plotly.io.templates) or
        definition.
    width: int (default `None`)
        The figure width in pixels.
    height: int (default `None`)
        The figure height in pixels.
    
    Returns
    -------
        plotly.graph_objects.Figure

